bingj.com 2012-11-01

# Microsoft Privacy Statement

Bing Privacy Statement

This privacy statement applies to Bing websites, services, products and applications that collect data and display these terms. It does not apply to other Microsoft products and services that do not link to the Bing Privacy Statement. 

Cookies & Similar TechnologiesCookies

When you use Bing services with a web browser, we will place one or more "cookies" on your machine. For example, Bing uses a cookie with a unique identifier known as the Search ID to operate the service and enable certain search features. If you sign into Bing or other Microsoft services using a Microsoft account, we will set or read one or more additional cookies. We use these cookies to operate Bing services and provide you a more relevant search experience. You can use your browser settings to remove or block cookies on your computer. 

We also use web beacons to help deliver cookies and compile analytics. These may include third-party web beacons, which are prohibited from collecting your personal information. 

Collecting Your InformationCollecting Your Information

When you use Bing services, Microsoft may collect many kinds of information in order to operate effectively and provide you the best products, services and experiences we can. We collect information when you register, sign in and use our sites and services. We also may get information from other companies. We collect this information in a variety of ways, including from web forms, technologies like cookies, web logging and software on your computer or other device.

When you conduct a search, Microsoft collects the following: 

  * Search term and time and date of your search
  * IP Address, browser configuration and approximate location
  * Any unique identifiers contained in the cookies

We store search terms (and the cookie IDs associated with search terms) separately from any account information that directly identifies the user, such as name, e-mail address, or phone numbers. We have technological safeguards in place designed to prevent the unauthorized correlation of this data and we remove the entirety of the IP address after 6 months, cookies and other cross session identifiers, after 18 months.

Bing provides search services to select partners and its users. Some examples include Yahoo! and Nokia. In order to provide these services, Bing services receive certain search related information from these partners that may include date, time, IP Address, a unique identifier and other search related data.

How We Use Your Personal InformationUsing Your Information

Microsoft uses the information we collect to operate, improve and personalize the products and services we offer. We also may use the information to communicate with you, for example, informing you about your account and security updates.

For Bing services, we use this information to provide you with relevant search results. We also use the information we collect to maintain and improve the quality, security and integrity of our services. For example we may use this information for research purposes and to improve the relevancy of Bing search results. This information is also necessary in order to detect and protect against security threats such as botnet attacks, click fraud, worms, and other threats. 

Finally, as described in the Display of Advertising section of this document, we may use search query data for the purpose of personalizing the ads we display to you as you use our services or those of our advertising partners.

Reasons We Share Your Personal InformationSharing Your Information

Except as described in this privacy statement, we won’t disclose your personal information to a third party without your consent.

We may share some search query data with selected third parties for research purposes. Before we do so, we remove all unique identifiers such as IP addresses and cookie IDs from the data. We also run the data through a process designed to remove identifiable information that users may have included in the search terms themselves (such as social security numbers or credit card numbers). Additionally, we require these third parties to keep the data secure and to not use the data for any other purposes. 

Please see Other Important Privacy Information for details about when we may disclose information, including with Microsoft affiliates and vendors; when required by law or to respond to legal process; to combat fraud or protect our interest; or to protect lives.

Accessing Your Personal Information and Search HistoryAccessing Your Information

When using a web browser, you can access and manage your information, including Search History, on Bing through the preferences page. In Bing search, using the search terms you enter and the results you click, Search History provides an easy way to revisit the sites and searches you've used before. You may clear your search history from appearing on the site by following the steps provided in [see your search history](http://onlinehelp.microsoft.com/en-us/bing/ff808483.aspx) (scroll down to "Clear search history"). Clearing your history removes it from the Search History service and prevents that history from being displayed on the site, but does not delete information from our standard search logs, which are retained and anonymized as described above. To remove your search history from Windows 8 applications, see the Windows 8 Applications section.

Bing Mobile, Maps and Location ServicesMobile and Location Services

If you have agreed to allow access to your location, we collect the following information to improve your search and mapping results, provide you deals for local businesses, and operate and improve our services: 

  * **Bing Search services and Bing Mobile applications:** The approximate location of your device will be sent to Microsoft along with search terms, time and date of your search and a unique identifier generated by the application. Refer to the documentation that came with your device for information about how to turn off location for an application.
  * **"Check In” and “Reminders”:** When you sign into these services, Microsoft stores the approximate location of your device along with your Microsoft account. To disable access to your device’s location by these services, go to the settings menu of the Bing Search application and turn location to “Off.” If you are using a browser to access Bing Search services, refer to the browser documentation to disable sharing your location for sites visited on that browser.
  * **Mapping features:** Features on Microsoft's sites and services are based in part on the Bing Maps service. When you submit information, such as an address to be viewed on a map, to the application, that application passes it to Bing Maps for processing.

Facebook PersonalizationFacebook Personalization

Bing uses Facebook Instant Personalization to provide a more relevant and useful search experience for Facebook users. 

This provides you with an enhanced experience that takes your Facebook social network into account as permitted by your Facebook privacy settings. 

Facebook currently powers the enhanced people search feature, so if you submit a search query while signed into Facebook that Bing classifies as a person’s name, we send the query to Facebook, which Facebook uses to return the relevant results. Facebook does not use this query information for any other purpose, and deletes it within 24 hours. You can turn off these Instant Personalization features at any time by going to <http://www.facebook.com/help/?faq=204873389548151>. 

Windows 8 Applications that Use Bing Search ServicesWindows 8 Applications

Syncing application settings helps keep your app settings up-to-date across PCs and devices running the app. If you sign in to Windows 8 with a Microsoft account or a domain account connected to a Microsoft account, Sync Your Settings will be turned on by default and will send some of your customized settings to the cloud to keep your PCs in sync. When you sign in to Windows 8 on another PC or device with the same Microsoft account, the service will download and apply those settings to the additional PC or device. These settings include:

  * Your favorites, including stocks, sports and news, depending on the app; 
  * Your settings, including weather units; and
  * Your history, including search history, if enabled.

Bing BarBing Bar

The Bing Bar gives you a quick, convenient way to search the internet, check your email, weather forecasts, traffic reports, road maps, and Facebook. (Some features may not be available in your country or region). When you use the Bing Bar, certain information is collected and shared with Microsoft and used in order to operate the Bing Bar services and to help improve Bing Bar and other Microsoft products and services, including information about your computer, your searches, addresses of websites you visit, and how you use Bing Bar. If you elect not to participate in the Improvement Program more limited information will be collected.

The Bing Bar provides a number of features and services which collect and use additional information as follows and are described further in the details sections.

  *  **Searching** with the Bing Bar
  *  **Autosuggest** to provide you with search suggestions
  *  **Bing Bar Experience Improvement Program** is an optional program to improve the quality and performance of our products and services.
  *  **AutoFill** Some older versions of the Bing Bar include an optional feature that can automatically fill out forms on Web sites with information such as your address, passwords, and credit card information so that you do not have to repeatedly type the same information or remember multiple passwords. 

ChildrenChildren

When a Microsoft site or service collects age information, it will block users under 13 or obtain consent from a parent or guardian before their child can use it. 

When consent is granted, the child’s account is treated much like any other account, including being able to communicate with other users.Parents can change or revoke consent as described in this privacy statement.

Display of AdvertisingAdvertising

Most of the online advertisements on Microsoft sites and services are displayed by Microsoft Advertising.  When we display online advertisements to you, we will place one or more cookies in order to recognize your computer when we display an ad to you.  Over time, we may gather information from the sites where we serve ads and use the information to help provide more relevant ads.

 **You may opt out of receiving targeted ads from Microsoft Advertising by visiting our[ opt-out page](http://choice.live.com/advertisementchoice/)**. 

Communication PreferencesCommunications

You can stop the delivery of future promotional email from Microsoft sites and services by following the specific instructions in the email you receive.  You also have the option of proactively making choices about the receipt of promotional email, telephone calls and postal mail from Microsoft by visiting and signing in to the [Promotional Communications Manager](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=243191).

Microsoft AccountMicrosoft Account

Microsoft account (formerly known as Windows Live ID and Microsoft Passport) is a service that allows you to sign into Microsoft products, web sites and services, as well as those of select Microsoft partners.When you create a Microsoft account, we ask you to provide certain information. When you sign into a site or service using your Microsoft account, we collect certain information in order to verify your identity on behalf of the site or service, to protect you from malicious account usage, and to protect the efficiency and security of the Microsoft account service. We also send certain information to a site or service you have signed into with your Microsoft account. 

To view additional details about Microsoft account, including how to create and use a Microsoft account, how to edit account information, and how we collect and use information relating to a Microsoft account, please click on Learn More. 

Other Important Privacy InformationOther Information

Learn more about

  * Non-Microsoft services that use Bing search
  * Why and with whom we share or disclose personal information
  * Protecting the security of personal information
  * Where we store and process information
  * Changes to our privacy statements
  * TRUSTe certification and enforcing our privacy statements 
  * How to contact us
